（ナルト）ヨタ！　頼む。
やめてくれってばよ。
Yota! Please!
Stop it!
ヨタ！
Yota!
ヨタ！！
《サクラ：ナルト！》
Yota!
《サクラちゃん？》
Naruto?!
Sakura?!
《あんた　ヨタって言ったわよね？
そっちにも来てるの？》
Did you just say "Yota"?!
Is he there too?!
《そっちって…　サクラちゃんの
ところにもいるのかよ？》
What do you mean, "there too"?
He's with you also?
《シカマル：サクラどころじゃねえ。
Not only Sakura!
But with us too!
俺たちのところにも
キバのところにも…》
Including Kiba!
《キバ：あぁ…
派手にやってくれてるぜ》
Oh boy... He's really going at it.
《ヨタが４人…》
There are four Yotas?
《チョウジ：ヨタ　怒ってるのかな？
I wonder if Yota is angry at us...
だから　みんなのところに…。
Maybe that's why he came to each of us.
Because we let him die.
僕たちのせいで
死んじゃったから…》
《ヨタは　幽霊じゃねぇぞ。
Yota is not a ghost.
穢土転生で操られてんだ。
He was reanimated
and is being controlled!
しっかりしろ　チョウジ》
Get your act together, Choji!
《ちょっと　待てよ。
Hold on a sec!
穢土転生って　影分身みたいに
そんなにいっぱい→
So with Reanimation,
you can be resurrected
よみがえらせることが
できんのかよ？》
lots of times like Shadow Clones?!
《これまでは　なかったが…》
Not until now...
《俺が　相手してんのは
間違いなくヨタだ。
I'm positive it's Yota I'm facing.
じゃあ
みんなのところにいるのは→
Which means, all of you could
be seeing that white guy!
あの　白いヤツかも
しれねえってばよ》
白ゼツか。
You mean, White Zetsu!
本物じゃないってこと？
So he's not the real one?!
でも　この雪はヨタの…。
But this snow is Yota's...
いや　本体が術をかけてりゃ
問題ねえ。
No...
As long as the real one is
performing the jutsu, it's possible.
というより　ヨタを操ってる誰かだ。
Or should I say,
the one controlling Yota.
みんな　きっとそいつらは
ヨタじゃねえ。
Everyone... These guys aren't Yota!
だから
みんなが苦しむことなんかない。
So you don't need to feel guilty!
痛みは　俺が引き受ける。
I'll take on your guilt! So...
だから　倒しちまってくれ。
ニセモンのヨタを！
Take them down...
Take down the Yota impostors!
ナルト…。
Naruto...
（ヨタ）フフフッ。
ごめんな　ヨタ。
Sorry, Yota...
softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
Lingering Snow
ヨタ！
Yota...
超倍化の術！
Super Expansion Jutsu!
影真似の術！
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
ヨタ！！
Yota!
ニセモンとはいえよ…。
Even if he is an impostor...
いくぜ　赤丸！
Let's go, Akamaru.
ざけんなよ。
You've gotta be kidding.
はぁ～！
ヨタ…。
Yota...
《あのとき俺たちは
ヨタを助けようとした。　けど…》
Back then, we tried to save Yota.
But...
((また　１人か…。
So I'm alone again...
じゃねえよ。　６人と１匹だ。
Not really.
There's six of us plus one dog!
みんなで来ちゃった。
We all came.
なっ…　あっ！
Huh? What—?
お前ら！
人んちにズカズカと入るんじゃ…。
You guys! You can't just
walk in uninvited...!
何言ってんの。
今まで寂しそうにしてたくせに。
That's no way to talk.
You looked so lonely right up 'til now.
ったく　いい天気だってのに→
Geez... It's so nice outside...
部屋の中いると　ますます誰も
寄りつかなくな…。
If you stay cooped up like this,
no one will want to...?!
うん？　雨が降ってる。
It's raining.
（２人）うん？
Huh?
ヨタか？
Is it Yota?
俺たちで　ヨタを奪い返すんだ。
We're going to get Yota back!
どこから来た？
Where are you from?
どこの里だ？
What village?
私　わからないよ…　難しいこと。
I don't... know...
about complicated stuff...
優しいこと言ってよ。
Ask me easy questions.
どこから来た？　どこの里だ？
Where are you from? What village?
埒が明かないな。
We're getting nowhere.
手荒になる前に
一度　三代目にお越し願おうか。
We should ask Lord Third to come
before things get more intense.
《幻術？　いや…》
Was it genjutsu...? No...
ギャーッ　ハハハハハッ！
コラ！　やめろ！
下りてこい！
Hey! Stop it!
Get down from there!
バーカ！　誰が下りるかってぇの！
Idiots! As if I'd do that!
俺は　うずまきナルト！
忍者だってばよ！
I'm Naruto Uzumaki! I'm a ninja!
（火影）なに！？
What?
ヤツは　問題の少年と一緒にいた
アカデミー生徒の１人です。
He's one of the students
from the Academy
who was with the boy in custody.
捕まえられるもんなら
捕まえてみろってばよ！
Try and catch me if you can!
里中の忍者　みんなこ～い！
All the ninja in the village!
Come and get me!
待て　この悪ガキが！
– That damned brat!
– Hold it!
天気雨…。
Sun showers?
まったく！
なんてバチ当たりなヤツだ。
He's such a pain in the butt...
三代目様の顔岩は
そりゃあ　もうメチャクチャらしい。
I heard Lord Third's
Mountainside Image
is badly damaged.
ああ　そうらしいな。
I heard that too.
この里で暮らしていながら
なぜ　そんなことができるんだ？
He lives in our village.
How could he do such a thing?
アタッ！
Yikes!
（２人）おっ？
何か見た？
Did you see anything?
いや…　ハハッ　気のせいだろ。
No.
It was probably my imagination.
だな。
Probably...
お願いだから　もう助けてよ。
Please, I beg you. Let me go...
うっ…　うぅ…。
影真似の術　成功！
Shadow Possession Jutsu complete!
（みんな）ヨタ！　ヨタ！
– Yota! Hey!
– Yota!
– Hey! Yota!
– Are you okay?
おい！
大丈夫？
みんな！
Everyone!
ハハハッ！
（みんな）ヒヒヒヒッ！
やっぱりすごいよ　シカマル！
Shikamaru, you're amazing, after all.
大人の忍者に
術をかけちゃうなんて。
You did a jutsu on grown-up ninja!
（いの）アンタ　ひょっとして天才？
Are you some kind of genius?
いや　まだまだひよっこだ。
Nope... He's still wet behind the ears.
チッ…。
Shucks!
動くな。
Don't move.
里の利益をおびやかす者は
子供といえど　容赦はしない。
Anyone who threatens
the welfare of the village
will be treated harshly,
even if they are children.
コイツは　スパイかもしれないんだぞ。
He could be a spy.
ふざけんな！！
You've gotta be joking!
コイツは…　ヨタは　そんなんじゃねえ！！
Yota isn't...
Yota isn't like that!
ヨタは…　俺の…。
Yota is... the first friend...
I've ever had!
俺の初めてできた友達だ！
友達…。
Friend...
うっ…。
わ…　私の…　友達！！
Yeah... My friend...!
ヨタ…。
Yota!
逃げるってばよ。
Run!
深ぇぞ　この川。
This river is deep.
でも　ここを越えないと…。
But we have to cross it...
もう追っ手が向かってるはずよ。
They're probably coming
after us already.
水の上が渡れたら…。
If only we could walk on water...
（キバ）行くっきゃねえよ！
（赤丸）ワンワン！
We have to do it.
行こう。　ヨタを自由なところへ。
Let's go someplace
where Yota can be free!
あっ！
ガハッ…。
ナルト！
Naruto!
チョウジ！　シカマル！
– Choji!
– Shikamaru!
プハッ…。
（みんな）ヨタ！
– Yota!
Yota!
ハア…　ハア…　ゴホッ　ゴホッ…。
ハア…　ハア…　ハア…。
ヨタ…　ありがとな…。
Yota... Thank you.
ヨタ！
Yota?!
(ヨタ！！))
Yota!
((みんな：ヨタ！　ヨタ！　ヨタ！
– Yota! Yota!
– Yota!
Yota!
ヨタ！
ヨタ？
Yota!
しっかりして！
（チョウジ）平気？　寒くない？
Get a grip, Yota!
ヨタ！　もう　大丈夫だから。
Yota...
It's all right now.
ヨタ…。
しっかりしなよ。
Yota...
Come on, wake up.
（赤丸）クゥーン…。
よかったね　みんな。
Thank goodness, everyone...
もう　大丈夫だからね。
It's okay now.
お前がだよ！
しっかりしてくれよ。　なぁ　ヨタ！
No, you're the one who's okay!
Snap out of it, Yota!
私は　もう…。
I'm already...
ダメだよ。　ヨタ！
No, Yota!
ごめん。　俺が　ムチャしなけりゃ…。
I'm sorry,
if I hadn't been so reckless...
俺のせいだ。
クゥーン…。
It's my fault...
もっと　いい手があったはず…
なのによ！
We should've tried a different way...
ヨタ！
ヨタ…　ごめん！
Yota!
Yota... I'm so sorry.
お別れだよ。
It's time for me to go.
何　言ってんだよ！？
これからも　俺たちは…。
What're you talking about?!
From now on, we're...
私は　みんなのこと　忘れない。
I'll never forget about you guys.
でも　みんなは
私のこと　忘れるんだよ。
But you guys, forget about me.
バカなこと　言ってんじゃねえ！
Don't be ridiculous!
忘れるわけ　ないだろ！
（シカマルたち）そうだよ！
How can we forget you?!
– Yeah, he's right!
– It's true, Yota!
忘れなきゃ　つらいよ。
You have to forget...
otherwise... it will be painful.
ヨタ…　俺は…。
Yota, I'm...
(ヨタ…))
Yo... ta...
《そして　俺たちは　ヨタを忘れた。
And so we forgot about Yota...
楽しかった　すべてを。
About all the fun we had...
みんなと友達だったことも。
That we were all friends...
And I was alone once again.
俺は　ひとりぼっちに戻った》
ヨタ…　俺は忘れたくなかった。
Yota...
I never wanted to forget.
If I were to forget you...
お前とのこと　忘れるくらいなら→
I'd rather live with
the guilt of letting you die...!
お前を死なせた後悔の中で
生きてたほうが　よっぽど…。
もう一度…　もう一度　ヨタを→
Yota, do I have to...
あんな目に
あわせなきゃなんねえのかよ！？
make you suffer one more time?!
耐えられるわけ　ないだろ…。
How can I bear that?!
これは…。
That's...
《ナルト…　私だよ　ヨタだよ》
Naruto... It's me. Yota!
《ヨタ…》
Yota...
It's our secret tin can telephone...
just between you and me.
《ナルトと私の秘密の糸電話だよ》
《これなら
穢土転生の術者に聞かれずに…》
Whoever is controlling him
won't be able to hear us!
《ナルト…　アンタの頭の中のその声！》
Naruto! That voice inside your head!
《ヨタ！》
《２人：ヨタ！》
Yota!
– Yota!
《ヨタじゃねえか！》
《ワン！》
It's Yota!
Sakura! Shikamaru! Ino!
Choji! Kiba! Akamaru!
《サクラ　シカマル　いの　チョウジ　キバ　赤丸》
《ごめん　ごめん…　ごめんね》
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
I'm so sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
《なんで謝るの？》
《俺たちは　お前を
助けることができなかった。
We couldn't save you.
We let you die...
死なせちまったんだ。
だから　みんな…》
That's why everyone's...
Naruto... Everyone...
《ナルトもね　みんなもね→
Don't worry yourselves over that.
気にすることなんか
何もないんだよ。
Because when I met you guys,
I was already dead.
だって　私はね
ナルトたちに会ったとき→
もう　死んでたんだもん》
I was reanimated,
then I met you guys.
《穢土転生でよみがえって
それで　ナルトたちに会ったんだ。
もう死んでたんだ。
I was already dead.
WEATHER FOR SALE
私は　天気を操る不思議な
力を持った一族に生まれて→
I was born into a clan that
possessed the strange ability
to control weather.
DISTANCE: 2.44 MILES
天気売りを商売にして
里から里へ旅して歩いた。
We went from village to village.
Selling weather was our trade.
私　一族のなかでも　特に
天気使いがうまかったんだよ》
Even in my clan...
I was especially good
at controlling the weather.
《でもね　生まれつき
体が弱くってね…。
But I was born very weak...
死んじゃったんだ。
and I died.
死んだんだけど
呼び止められちゃった》
I died, but... I wasn't allowed to die.
((キャーッ！))
《カブト：ヨタ　役立てよ》
Yota... Be useful now...
《ヨタ：蛇とメガネがね
穢土転生のテストだっていって→
The snake... and the glasses fellow...
They said they were
testing Reanimation and...
ナルトたちの里に
私を置いていったんだよ。
they left me in your village, Naruto.
私はね　悲しかった》
I was... so sad.
ヨタ…。
Yota...
《サクラ：ホントに　ごめんね。
一緒にいてあげられなくて》
Yota... We're so sorry
we couldn't stay with you.
Oh no, don't be sorry.
《ううん　謝ることないよ。
You know, it was so tough
when I was alive...
あのね　私　生きてるとき
つらくて　つらくて。
I was always alone,
no matter where I went.
どこにいても
ずっと　ひとりぼっちだった。
でもね　死んでから
ひとりぼっちじゃなくなった。
But after I died,
I wasn't alone anymore.
みんなに会って
ホントに楽しかったんだよ。
I met all of you...
And it was so much fun.
あの川で　また
よみがえってしまったけど…。
I was resurrected at
that river once more...
あれからまた１人で　死にながら
生き続けてきたけど…。
And I had to live alone all over again,
although I was dead...
みんなとの思い出があるから
つらくなんかなかった》
But I had my memories of
all of you, so it wasn't hard.
And it's too bad it had to be this way...
《それに　こんなかたちだけど
みんなに　また会えた。
but I got to see you again!
You've grown up so much, Naruto.
大きくなったね　ナルト。
You too, Sakura...
サクラも　シカマルも　いのも　チョウジも…。
And Shikamaru...
Ino too... and Choji.
キバも　赤丸も元気そうだ》
Kiba and Akamaru,
you look like you're doing well!
ヨタ　だったら　楽しもうぜ。
Yota! So let's have more fun!
Who cares about Reanimation?!
穢土転生なんて関係ねえ。
前みたいに　一緒に　喜んで
怒って　悲しんで　楽しむんだよ。
It'll be like old times! All together!
We'll be happy, and mad, and sad,
and have fun!
What... is this?!
《なに　これは…》
Kon kon kon...
コンコンコン…。
《嬉しいよ　私は楽しいよ》
I'm so happy... I'm having fun...
ヨタ！
Yota!
Naruto... Everyone... Thank you!
《ナルト　みんな　ありがとう。
楽しいまま　私はいくよ。
I'm going to go
while I'm still happy.
今度はね　みんな私のこと
忘れちゃやだよ。
Now this time, don't forget me.
I want you to remember me.
覚えてておくれよ》
No, Yota!
ダメだ　ヨタ！
《ヨタ：これで思い残すことはない。
I have no regrets now...
ホントに死ねる。　バイバイ　ナルト　みんな。
I can really die now.
Bye-bye, Naruto... Everyone!
明日も晴れますように》
I hope tomorrow is a sunny day!
ヨタ！
Yota...!
（ヨタ）フフフッ…。
I was tired of walking and didn't know what I should do
aruki tsukarete tohou ni kureta
my teacher told me to go towards a bright future
akarui mirai e sensei wa iu kedo
but which way should I go to find the light?
docchi ni aruitara hikari wa sasu kana
I have no idea at the moment so let's go
toriaezu wakaranai kedo ikouze
don't tell me things I want to hear
kirei goto nanka maji kan kanben desu
just give me something so powerful that it hurts
itai kurai tsuyoi yatsu wo choudai
I'm rebelling against the ordinary life
arikitari na mainichi ni hankou desu
burning up the mic with our rock
tagire m i c oretachi no rock
I can hear you are screaming
kimino koe ga kikoeru
that's the only thing that's real, let it explode
sore dake wa real sa hajikero
this song
kono uta
i can hear you are screaming
I'm running through the night on impulse
tsuki ugokasare shoudou no mama ni yoru wo kakenda
can't you see can't you see can't you see my face
I want to sense this moment not just the words, I want to sense you
kotoba ja nai ima dake wo kanjitetai kimi wo kanjitetai
i can hear you are screaming
keep on shouting and open the door to tomorrow
sakebi tsuzukete ashita no tobira wo kojihirakerunda
don't worry don't worry don't worry baby
I want to believe in us, not anyone else, I want to believe in my dream
dareka ja nai oretachi wo shinjitetai yume wo shinjitetai
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
I didn't expect to lose
this many of my pawns.
So then, what's my next move?
美空ひばりです。
Maybe I'll stir things up
on the battlefield.
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
To think I'd have to resort to
sending in you guys as well.
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
But I think you'll be useful
in taking back the powerful pieces
that I've lost...
２時間スペシャル。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Reanimated Allied Forces"
That's what you
sacrificial pieces are for.